[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So we understand how a computer works.
我们知道了电脑是怎么工作的
We understand how a human works.
也了解了人是怎么反应的
Now we need to understand the data.
现在我们需要理解数据
The different kinds of data and
各种各样的数据
how data works its way through a data visualization system.
数据在数据可视化系统中是怎么运行的
And so there's a Data Visualization Framework that helps us
数据可视化框架可以帮助我们理解
understand how data is processed for visualization.
数据可视化的操作流程
First, data's available to us from a variety of sources, so
首先 我们可以从各种途径获取数据
there's a Data Collection operation.
这是一个数据收集的流程
That basically combines the data from a bunch of different sources and
在这个流程中 各种原始数据基本整合
processes it into one package for visualization.
使之成为为可视化做准备的数据包
Then there is a Mapping Layer, this mapper that takes the data, and
接下来是映射层 映射器获取数据
the data's abstract and whatever computational representation it may be in,
以及数据的简要 或者其他计算机形式的表达
and it converts it into some geometric representation,
然后把这些数据转化为几何图形
something concrete, that then a Graphics Layer can take and display.
这些具体的图形 在图形应用层可以被读取和展示
And that prepares it for visualization, for
这就为可视化做了准备
communication across this visual channel for human perception.
也会人们视觉感知的交流做了准备
So the Data Layer Is responsible for finding the data,
所以数据层主要负责寻找数据
collecting the data from different sources.
收集各种来源的数据
Making sure those sources, which may have the data in different formats,
我们要确定这些 可能含有不同的格式数据
that the data can be combined into a uniform data store.
可以被整合成统一的格式
And making sure that the data is related between different sources properly.
同时也要确定 来源不同的数据是相互关联的
And then there's some analysis and aggregation to run statistics on the data,
然后需要对数据进行分析和汇总 以便于对数据进行统计
make sure the data is collected at the right frequency.
还有确定以合适的频度来收集数据
And then that data, once it's in a single package, is sent to the Mapping Layer,
然后这些数据一旦被整合到一个数据包中 就传送到映射层
which assigns the geometry to corresponding data channels, and
其根据数据的不同选定相应的几何方法
can also perform other rather sophisticated data processing operations,
也可进行其它较复杂的数据处理
things like contouring which take grid samples and convert them into outlines
比如轮廓处理 即将网格类选样数据转化成轮廓
of contours that can be useful for understanding what's going on in the data.
可以用来理解数据内部的机理
And finally, there's a Graphics Layer and
最后是图形层
this converts the geometry into a displayable image as we saw last week.
这里几何图形讲被转化成 我们上周看的图片
It applies Decorations to the geometry.
几何图形被适当装饰
It assigns color.
配上颜色
It shades the geometry.
和明暗度
It's also responsible for managing the interactions.
同时包括交互处理
The user input during the visualization.
也就是用户在可视化过程中输入
So that's the framework for data visualization.
所以这就是数据可视化的框架
As we look at the actual data involved and that mapping operation,
当我们查看实际的数据和映射流程
it's important to understand some fundamental features of data,
了解数据的基本特征十分重要
the types of data that are out there.
以及数据的类型
And so data can either be Discrete or Continuous.
数据可以是离散型数据 或者连续性数据
Discrete data has Discrete values, there's no between values.
离散型数据含有离散值 每个值之间没有其他值
Whereas Continuous data has values between neighboring values that are possible.
但是对于连续性数据来说 在相邻的两个值之间可能存在另外的值
And then there's comparable data so that the data can be compared to each other or
同时也存在有序数据（可比数据） 指两个数据可以相互比较
Unordered data where the values are not comparable.
及无序数据 即数据之间没有可比性
So we look at all the possibilities of Discrete and Continuous data of Ordered
所以当我们回顾所有的可能性 有序和无序数据以及离散和连续数据
and Unordered, and you get the different kinds of data that you'll be dealing with.
你可能会面对不同的数据
For example, Ordinal data.
比如 有序数据
Ordinal data is data that's ordered, but discreet.
有序数据是有序的离散数据
Things like shirt sizes.
比如衣服的尺码大小
You can say a medium shirt is going to be larger than a small shirt or
你可以说中号的衣服比小号的要大
a large shirt is going to be smaller than a medium shirt.
或者说一件大衬衫比中号小些
But there may not be values of a shirt size between medium and large.
但是中号和大号衣服之间 可能不存在别的型号（值）
And these can be quantitative which are discrete and ordered.
所以这些数据就是 离散且有序
For example the counting numbers one, two, three.
比如连续的数据1，2，3
There's not one point five.
但是没有0.5
So there's no value between 1 and 2 in our counting numbers.
所以在1和2之间 也没有其他的值
So they're discrete, but yet 2 is greater than 1 so they're ordered.
所以他们是离散的 同时 2大于1 所以他们也是有序的
And so those are examples of discrete Ordered values.
所以以上例子都是离散有序数值
You can have Continuous Ordered values, and
同时也有连续有序数据
these are common real numbers, the real number line and so on.
这些就是通常的实数 实数轴等等
and values that we'd use, for example, for altitude or temperature or
我们经常用的值 比如海拔高度 温度等
any continuous field of values.
以及各种连续数值
You can also have Unordered data in discrete and continuous forms.
同时你也会见到 无序的离散和连续数据
The discrete form of Unordered data can be Nominal or Categorical.
无序的离散数据 可能是标称数据或者分类数据
Things like shapes are examples of nominal data.
比如说形状 就是标称数据
They're not ordered.
他们没有顺序
A square, circle and a triangle.
长方形 圆形 三角形
You wouldn't say that the square is greater than or
你不会说 长方形比圆形大
less than a circle, because there's no order between them.
或者比圆形小 因为他们之间没有顺序
You could have categories.
也有分类型数据
Different nationalities, or other other categories for
如不同的国籍 或者其它的类别
data that may not necessarily be comparable and those are discreet.
那些不可比较但是离散的数据
You can also have continuous values that are Unordered
你也会看到无序的连续数据
often Cyclic values are like this so directions or
一般是循环数据
cues, you wouldn't say that north is any greater or less than east.
比如方向或者色调 你不会说北比东要大
And you can having angle going from 0 to 360 in degrees but after you get a 360
比如0到360度的角度 当超过360度后
degrees, you go back to 0 degrees and so any one is not greater than any other.
又回重新回到0度 没有谁大于谁
And then hues you could have red, green, yellow, blue and
又如色调中有红色 绿色 黄色 蓝色
you may not say that red is any greater than green and so these values
你不会说红色比绿色要大
are continuous there are colors between red and green, but you wouldn't
这些值是连续的 在红色和绿色之间存在别的颜色
think of red as being greater than or less than green, so they're unordered.
你不会认为红色比绿色大或者小 所以他们是无序的
And finally, when we're treating data as variables, in science,
最后 我们把数据当作变量
you may recall Independent Variables and Dependent Variables.
在科学中 你也许回忆起有 自变量和因变量
And when Independent Variables change,
当自变量改变时
they can have an effect on Dependent Variables.
对因变量也会造成影响
That same notion happens in the data we get from, for example, Databases.
这个概念同样发上在数据中 比如在数据库中
And so you'll have Key Value pairs, and
所以你会遇到键值对
Databases will store an index and then a value associated with that index.
以及数据库将储存一个索引 然后一个数据值将和索引关联起来
And as the Key changes the resulting value will change.
当关键值改变时 结果值也会相应改变
So you have this Independent, Dependent relationship.
所以就形成了 自变和因变的关系
In Data Warehouses the Independent Variable is often a Dimension,
在数据仓库中 自变量一般是一个维度
something that's changing that represents Dimension.
他的变化往往代表一个维度
And then the Dependent Variable is a measure that's happening
而因变量往往是量度
as a result of that Dimension.
它是前面的那一维度的结果
So a dimension might be time, and
比如维度可能是时间
then the measure might be the temperature at that time of the day.
然后量度可能是一天中 各时段温度
And so as the time of the day changes,
所以随着一天时间的变化
which is an Independent Variable, you would have a Dependent Variable,
也就是一个自变量 将影响着因变量
the Measure, being the temperature at that time of the day changing.
即温度 也会随着时间而变化
And you can store that in a Database as a bunch of times of the day and
你可以把这些信息存在数据库中 即一天中不同的时间
then the temperature at that time of the day as a bunch of Key Value pairs.
和各时间对应的温度 即构成为了键值对
And so the data is basically stored in these Independent, Dependent
数据一般就由这些 不同的自变量和因变量的关系组成
relationships in a variety of names depending on the context of the data.
这些关系名称可应情况而不同
So the important thing to remember, the three fundamental kinds of data.
重要的是 我们要记住 这三种不同形式的数据
There's Nominal data, there's Ordered data, and there's Quantitative data.
他们是标称数据 有序数据 以及定量数据
And we'll be using those distinctions when we determine how that data ends up being
我们将根据这些区别来决定
displayed in a visualization system.
数据怎样在可视化系统中展示
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community